（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       ninjacloud
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（緑間(みどりま)）まさか—
I didn't think you would actually make it this far.
本当に勝ち上がってくるとは
思わなかったのだよ
But it ends here.
だがここまでだ
（黒子(くろこ)）
誠凛(せいりん)は決して弱くはありません
Seirin is not weak.
負けません
We will not lose.
（緑間）まったく 心外なのだよ
How disappointing.
（火神(かがみ)）くっ…
You think you can beat us with that?
（緑間）
その程度で出し抜いたつもりか
Do your worst.
やれるものなら やってみろ
（日向(ひゅうが)）うっ ううっ
（大坪(おおつぼ)）速攻！
There!
（日向）緑間！
Midorima!
Keep running.
（黒子）走っててください
（火神）はっ
（歓声）
（観客）うわあ 来た スリー
It's a three pointer!
（黄瀬(きせ)）均衡が崩れた
（笠松(かさまつ)）これで流れは秀徳(しゅうとく)だ！
The deadlock has been broken!
Shutoku's in control now!
What?
（緑間）何だと？
（火神）フンッ おりゃ！
Episode 11
That's Not It
They got them back in a second!
（観客１）一瞬でやり返したぞ
（観客２）すげえ！
Amazing!
（大坪･木村(きむら)）なっ…
Wha—
（リコ）なっ
（小金井(こがねい)）何なんだよ 今のは…
What was that?
（土田(つちだ)）コートの端から端まで
ぶった切ったぞ
That cut straight from one end of the court to the other.
くっ… 黒子
Kuroko...
I'm sorry.
すみません
そう簡単に第１クオーターを
取られると困ります
I can't let you take the first quarter that easily.
They can pass like that?
（高尾(たかお)）あんなパスもあんのかよ
（春日(かすが)）おいおい
イチローのレーザービームかよ
Hey, what was that, Ichiro's laser beam?
バスケだぞ
This is basketball!
This is the first time I've seen that too.
（日向）オレも初めて見た
But thanks to him, the flow of the game hasn't changed.
けど おかげで流れは
まだ変わってない
This game...
まだ…
（黒子）勝負は…
is just...
（火神）これからだろ！
getting started!
（宮地(みやじ)）フン！
（観客１）緑間だ！
It's Midorima!
Is he going to shoot another rainbow three?
（観客２）また打つのか
超高弾道スリー！
Midorimacchi, you could've made that shot.
緑間っち
今のは自分で打とうと思えば
いけたんじゃ…
I see.
（笠松）なるほどね
（黄瀬）え？
Huh?
（中谷(なかたに)）ふ〜ん
（中谷）へ〜え
I was already surprised by how little presence he had,
見失うほど影薄いってだけでも
ビックリなのに—
but he can pass like that too.
あんなパスもあるのか 彼
あんな緑間封じが
あるんだね ふむ…
They can shut down Midorima that way.
う〜ん
どうしようかなあ…
What should we do?
Midorimacchi's been shut down?
緑間っちが 封じられてる？
あの少年の回転式長距離パスでな
Yeah, with that kid's spinning long distance pass.
緑間のシュートは—
Midorima's team returns to defense during the long hang time of his shots,
その長い滞空時間中に
ディフェンスに戻り—
and that's good for preventing fast breaks.
速攻を防ぐメリットもある
However, not everyone goes back.
だが全員戻るわけじゃねえ
Just in case he misses,
万一 外したときのために
残りはリバウンドに備えてる
they leave someone to rebound the ball.
その滞空時間が あだになる
That hang time bites them in the ass.
If Midorima can go back, Kagami can also run back.
緑間が戻れるってことは
火神も走れるってことだ
They can counter Midorima with a super fast break by running past him.
戻った緑間の
さらに後ろまで貫通する—
超速攻がカウンターで来る
だから緑間は打てない
That's why Midorima can't shoot.
But the timing and decision to show us that pass
にしても そのパスを見せつける
タイミングと判断力…
and the confidence to complete it...
一発で成功させる度胸…
It confirms things.
再認識したぜ
I can see how he played at Teiko with you.
あいつ ああ見えてオマエと
帝光中にいただけのことはある
百戦錬磨だ
He's a battle-hardened warrior.
（高尾）ふん あんなんでウチが
抑えられるとか思われちゃ困るなあ
We can't have people think this is all it takes to shut us down.
（大坪）はっ
（伊月(いづき)･水戸部(みとべ)）あっ
Shutoku got them right back!
（観客）秀徳もすぐ返した
Shutoku
Seirin
（リコ）あは！
（観客１）おおっ すぐに返した！
They got it right back!
Seirin's passes don't make any sense, but they're amazing!
（観客２）誠凛のパス
わけ分かんねぇ！ けどすげぇ！！
This is it.
ここだねえ
Takao, Kimura, change marks.
おーい 高尾 木村
マークチェンジ
高尾 11番につけ
Takao, get on No. 11.
Seirin
Shutoku
He's marking Kuroko?
（日向）黒子のマーク？
It doesn't matter who's on him.
（降旗(ふりはた)）誰がついても一緒だろ？
Nobody can keep up with how invisible he is.
（河原(かわはら)）見失うほど影薄いんだぜ
（リコ）いきなり
直接的な形にしてきたわね
They're already taking a direct approach.
What are they trying to do?
どういうつもり？
（伊月）このパス…
That pass!
There's no doubt about it. He has it too!
やっぱり—
こいつも持ってる
I knew this would happen.
（高尾）こうなると思ったんだわ
Shin would say it's our fate to fight against each other,
まっ 真(しん)ちゃん風に言うなら
“運命なのだよ”
オレとオマエがやりあうのは
フン しかしまさか
こんなに早く対決できるとはねえ
but I didn't think we'd face each other so soon.
It occurred to me the first time we met.
初めて会ったときから
思ってたんだよ
You and I are the same kind of person.
オレとオマエは同じ人種だって
同じ１年だし？
We're both first years too.
パスさばくのが
なりわいの選手としてさ
Passing is our bread and butter.
So I guess you could say I hate you
だからねえ
ぶっちゃけなんつーの？
because you're like me.
あれ… 同族嫌悪？
I just don't want to lose to you.
オマエには負けたくねえんだわ
なんか！
What do you think you're doing?
どういうつもりだ
No matter how fast Takao is,
高尾がいくら速いからって
そういう問題じゃねぇぞ 黒子は
that's not the way to handle Kuroko.
（緑間）黒子の力など百も承知だ
I am already familiar with Kuroko's abilities.
You will see soon enough.
すぐに分かるのだよ
I've never felt this before, but I think
ってか今までこんな感覚に
なったことねえんだけどな
it's because there's something different about you.
オマエがたぶん…
どっか他と違うからじゃね？
I'm sorry.
すみません
そういうこと言われたの初めてで…
No one has ever said that to me before,
so I don't know what to say.
困ります
What?
But I think I have a similar feeling.
けど…
僕にも似た感覚はちょっとあります
That's good.
（高尾）いーね やる気満々じゃ…
We're ready to go.
Hey, wait!
ちょっと待て〜い！！
いきなり姿くらますって
どんだけ礼儀知らずだ オマエ！！
Just how rude are you, suddenly disappearing like that?
Just kidding.
なーんてな
Hyuga's free! Go!
（土田）日向フリー！ 行けー！！
Seriously?!
（火神）マジかよ
Too bad, Kuroko.
残念だったな 黒子
That's the first time he's made a mistake.
あいつの失敗なんて初めてじゃ…
（伊月）たぶん失敗じゃない
（日向）え？
No, that wasn't a mistake.
Takao's got the same eagle eye I have.
高尾も持ってるんだ
オレのイーグルアイと同じ—
No...
いや—
His hawk eye's field of vision is even larger than mine.
視野の広さはオレより上の
ホークアイを
Kuroko's misdirection relies on redirecting the gaze of other players.
（伊月）黒子の使う
ミスディレクションは—
黒子を見ようとする視線をそらす
However, the hawk eye allows him to see everything.
だがホークアイは全体を見る能力
He's not just trying to watch Kuroko.
黒子１人を見ようとはしていない
In other words, Kuroko's misdirection doesn't work against Takao.
つまり高尾には
ミスディレクションが効かない
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Seirin.......................................Shutoku
Seirin, time out.
（審判）誠凛
タイムアウトです
I can't believe he can keep up with Kuroko.
（日向）
まさか黒子をとらえるなんて…
I didn't think there was anyone like that.
（リコ）あんな天敵がいるとはね…
We're in trouble.
ぶっちゃけ ピンチだわ
あーらら 誠凛 困っちゃったね〜
Uh-oh.
Seirin's in trouble.
Do not let your guard down.
気を抜くな 黒子は
これで終わるようなやつじゃない
Kuroko will not go down so easily.
It's fine.
大丈夫だって！
影の薄さ取ったらただのザコだろ？
Once you take away his lack of presence, he's worthless.
オレがあいつのことを
なぜ気に食わないか分かるか？
Do you know why I don't like him?
Because I respect Kuroko.
それは黒子のことを
認めているからだ
身体能力で
優れているところはひとつもない
He has no physical strengths.
He cannot do anything by himself.
１人では何もできない
Despite that, he wore the same uniform as the rest of us at Teiko
にもかかわらず帝光でオレたちと
同じユニフォームを着て—
and led the team to victory.
チームを勝利に導いた
His abilities are nothing like ours.
あいつの強さは
オレたちとはまったく違う
His strengths are of another kind.
異質の強さなのだよ
だから気に食わん
That is why I don't like him.
Because a man I respect has chosen to bury himself with a team that cannot fully utilize his abilities.
オレの認めた男が
力を生かしきれないチームで—
望んで埋もれようと
しているのだからな
おい オマエ まさかこのまま
やられっぱなしじゃねえだろうな
Hey, don't tell me you're going to keep letting them shut you down.
Well, I suppose I don't like it.
まぁ やっぱちょっと嫌です
That's what I like to hear!
よく言った！
（火神）カントク！
（リコ）あ？
Coach!
Let us keep going like this, please.
このまま行かせてくれ… ださい
Like this?
このまま？
You know your misdirection won't work against Takao, right?
高尾君にはミスディレクションは
効かないのよ
大丈夫？
Are you going to be okay?
大丈夫… じゃないです
困りました
I'm not okay.
I have a problem.
Yeah, I see...
うん… そう
I mean, what are you going to do?
ってかオイ どうすんだ！
（審判）タイムアウト終了です！
The time out is over!
Take care of Takao.
ひとまず高尾は任せるぞ
Okay.
はい
Let's go say hi.
（火神）こっちもアイサツしようか
手土産の新技もあるしな
We've got a new play to cram down their throats.
Hey, did you come up with a plan?
よう 何か対策考えてきた？
I'm still thinking.
まだ考え中です
You're doing what?
（高尾）何それっ！？
Two games in one day is brutal.
（日向）やっぱ１日２試合は
ヤベエな　正直 もう体だりぃ
I'm already exhausted.
And we're up against the king, Shutoku.
（伊月）
しかも相手は王者秀徳…
If we let them get too far ahead, catching up will be difficult.
大きく離されたら
再び追いつくのはかなり厳しい
Seirin....................................Shutoku
We're controlling the pace of the game.
（大坪）
ペースはオレたちがつかんでる
Stay on the attack!
いつもどおり攻めるぞ！
A-Are the upperclassmen already short of breath?
せ 先輩たち
もう息切れ始まってないスか？
It's still only the first quarter.
まだ第１クオーターなのに…
It's okay.
大丈夫
This game definitely depends on Kuroko and Kagami, who we rested.
この試合 温存しといた黒子君と
火神君にかかっているのは確かよ
However, that's not all.
でもそれだけじゃない
What is that?
（福田(ふくだ)）何スか それ？
One I broke before.
（リコ）この前折ったやつ…
Broke?
折った！？
After we lost last year.
（リコ）去年 負けてからね
Hey, Coach.
（日向）なあカントク
How can I make shots even while under pressure?
プレッシャーのかかる
大事な場面でも決めるには—
どうすればいい？
Huh?
All our players are my age,
ウチの部員はみんなタメだし—
and I'm not a very good leader.
正直オレに
強力なリーダーシップはない
I want to be able to lead everyone with my play.
だから…
せめてプレーでみんなを
引っ張れるようになりたいんだ
ふーん
You have to get used to it.
慣れておけばいいのよ
Always play under pressure and you'll get used to it.
（リコ）つまり普段から
プレッシャーをかけて—
慣れておけばいいのよ
For example, break one of your precious
例えば練習中
シュートを外した数だけ—
Sengoku warrior figures for every shot you miss during practice.
日向君の大事にしてる
戦国武将フィギュアをへし折るとか
うぅ〜ん…
（日向）うぅ〜ん…
（リコ）はは…
Okay, I'll do it!
おっしゃ… それやる
What? Really?
（リコ）えっ？ やるの！？
Masamune!
Yukimura!
幸村(ゆきむら)〜
Shingen!
信玄(しんげん)〜
Who cares about kings? Go die!
王者がなんぼのもんじゃい
死ね！
His personality suffered a little though.
ちょっとだけ
性格がゆがんだけど—
日向君は
大事なシュートは絶対決めるわ！
Hyuga will always hit important shots.
Stealing a steal!
スティールのスティール…
黒子のほうが封じられてる！
Kuroko's been shut down!
It isn't like Kurokocchi to repeat the same mistakes.
（黄瀬）らしくねっスよ 黒子っち
同じミスを繰り返すなんて…
What are you doing?
何をボーッとしているのだよ
We are doing everything we can.
こちらは本気なのだよ
もっと必死に守れよ
Defend harder.
My shooting range isn't that short.
オレのシュートレンジは
そんな手前ではないのだよ
He's shooting from the center line?
（火神）
センターラインからだと！？
The high arc extends his range.
（日向）高いループは
長距離を飛ばすため…
This must be that bad feeling I had earlier.
前に感じた違和感の正体は これか
ハーフコートすべてが
シュート範囲
The entire half of the court is within his shooting range!
This is Midorima's true power!
これが緑間の真の力！
Seirin....................................Shutoku
ここまで戻れば—
As long as I'm back here,
you cannot get behind me with Kuroko's passes.
黒子のパスで後ろを取るなど
不可能なのだよ
But it's all irrelevant.
だが そもそも関係ないのだよ
My shots are three points,
オレのシュートは３点
オマエたちのカウンターは２点
and your counter is only two.
Even if we do nothing, the gap will still grow wider.
何もしなかったとしても
差は開いていく
You've got something interesting there,
おもしれーもん
持ってんじゃねぇか！
だが…
but...
A three?
（緑間）スリーだと！？
（高尾）あいつ
アウトサイドシュートは苦手じゃ…
I thought he wasn't good from the outside.
If it goes in, that's fine.
（火神）そのまま入りゃ
それでいいし—
If it misses,
外れたら—
自分でブチこむ！
I'll dunk it myself!
（観客１）うわあ 何だ 今の！？
What was that?
A one-man alley-oop?
（観客２）１人アリウープ！？
こいつ…
That guy...
Nice.
（黒子）ナイスです
So nice how nice it was.
（伊月）ナイスじゃないっスか！
Izuki, seriously, stop.
（日向）伊月
ホントもうやめて それ
Seirin..............................Shutoku
One basket behind.
（リコ）ワンゴール差
このままなら 何とか…
At this rate, we might be able to...
That was a pretty good shot for you.
君らなりのいいシュートなのだよ
However...
だが…
W-What are you doing?
（火神）なっ… にやってんだよ
オイ そっから何メートルあると…
How many meters do you think you're...
ウソ… だろ！？
You're kidding!
I told you, it's not that short.
“そんな手前ではない”と
言ったはずなのだよ
My shooting range is the entire court.
オレのシュートレンジは
コートすべてだ
The first quarter is over.
（審判）第１クオーター終了
インターバル２分入ります
We'll have a two minute break!
Who hits that shot?
（リコ）あんなの決める 普通！？
We've got something bigger to worry about than the score.
点差以上にキツイのもらったわね…
Kuroko, has he always been able to do that?
黒子君 あれ 昔から？
No, I only knew he could shoot as far as the half line.
いえ 僕の知ってる彼の距離は
ハーフラインまでです
That's the first time I've seen him shoot from there.
あんなところから打てるのは
初めて知りました
I've seen videos of NBA players make that shot during practice,
ＮＢＡ選手が—
練習で決めた映像は
見たことあるけど…
試合中に狙ってとか
ありえないぞ
but trying that in an actual game is ridiculous.
冗談きついぜ “キセキの世代”
The Generation of Miracles are ridiculous.
How are we supposed to stop that?
ってか あんなん
どうやって止めんの？
They'll try to stop Midorima first.
（中谷）あちらさんはまず
何とか緑間止めにくるよね うん
There's a few ways they could do it, but let's see...
まぁいくつかパターンあるけど
どうしよっかなあ う〜ん…
Coach.
（緑間）監督
（中谷）ん？
第２クオーター全部
オレにボールください
Give me the ball for the entire second quarter.
Coach, can I hit him?
（宮地）監督
こいつ殴ってもいい？
Miyaji, why don't you throw a pineapple at him?
（木村）宮地
パイナップル投げるか
My family runs a produce store.
ウチ八百屋だし
（高尾）ギャハハハ！
どんだけ唯我独尊だよ！
Just how self-centered are you?
I love it!
マジ好き そういうの！
No matter how they come at us,
どんな手でこようが
すべて オレがたたき潰す
I will shut them down.
ふ〜ん うん よし
Okay. Let's call that three of your selfish actions for the day and do it.
今日のワガママ３回分で
手を打とう
Seriously, Coach?
マジすか 監督！？
You know I'm at my limit.
分かってんだろうな
オレもうギリだぞ
If that's what the coach says, I have no choice.
監督が言うならしょうがねぇ
前半は好きにしろ
Do what you want for the first half,
（大坪）ただし負けたら…
（緑間）うぐ…
but if we lose...
You have to stop Midorima!
とにかく緑間君を止めるわよ！
What?
（正邦(せいほう)選手たち）はぁっ！？
（緑間）その程度の奇策で
ひるむと思うか！
You think you can stop me with that?
Their real objective's coming up, Midorimacchi.
（黄瀬）本当の狙いは
この後っスよ 緑間っち！
おいおい 後ろからとか
ヤボなことしなさんな
Hey, now. Don't do crude stuff like that!
Kuroko's back tip...
（リコ）黒子君のバックチップを…
（黄瀬）読んでた？
They saw it coming?
（火神）クソッ！
黒子が無理ならオレがっ…
Damn it, if Kuroko can't do it, I will!
Stop me? Impossible.
（緑間）止めるか？
無理だな
（火神）こいつスリーだけじゃねぇ
速さも…
He's not just about shooting threes. He's fast too!
Don't get in my way, Takao.
（緑間）余計なことするな 高尾
（高尾）照れんなって
What are you trying to say?
Damn that monster.
（火神）クソッ！ バケモンがっ！
This is ridiculous!
（リコ）そんな！
Can they not do anything
高尾君がいるかぎり…
with Takao on the court?
（リコ）２人は何もできないの！？
（火神）ヤバ！
どっからでも打てるってことは—
Crap! He can shoot from anywhere
if he gets away from me for even a second...
一瞬でもマーク外したら…
（黄瀬）一番
カッチョイイシュート？
The coolest shot?
That'd be the dunk.
そりゃダンクっスよ
It's the best for the guy doing it and the people watching!
やるほうも見るほうも 一番
スカッとするじゃないスか！
That's why you are no good.
だからオマエはダメなのだ
より遠くから決めたほうが
いいに決まっているのだよ
Shooting from farther away is obviously the best,
since it's worth three points.
なぜなら３点もらえるのだから
Midorima, you're usually smart,
緑間君って頭いいのに
たまにアホですよね
but sometimes you can be stupid.
（緑間）なっ 何ぃ！？
（黄瀬）黒子っち ストレート
W-What?
Kurokocchi, you're so blunt.
２点ずつと３点ずつなら多いほうが
いいに決まっているだろう！
Between two and three points, more is obviously better.
What are you, a child?
子供ですか
フン
シンプルだからこそ真理なのだよ
いずれオレが証明してやろう
The truth is simple.
I will prove it to you someday.
There it is! That's two in a row for Midorima!
Shutoku
（観客）来たぁ！ 緑間２連続！
（日向）伊月 ボール回せ！
Izuki, give me the ball!
We can't rely on those two!
あいつらだけに頼ってねえで
オレらも攻めんだ！
We have to go for it ourselves!
No matter how much you score,
いくらか返したところで
オレのシュートは止められない
you cannot stop my shots.
No you don't!
させるかぁっ！
It's so high!
（火神）高(たけ)ぇ…
モーションに入ったら止められ…
Once he starts his motion, I can't stop it...
At this rate, I'm more worried about my heart than the score.
（日向）このままじゃ
点差以上に 心が—
My heart's gonna break!
心が折られる
（観客１）うわぁ ３連続！
Three in a row!
Midorima's unstoppable!
（観客２）緑間が止まらねぇ！！
ワンサイドか？
This is one-sided!
Seirin..........................................Shutoku
（リコ）こんな…
一体どうやって止めればいいの！？
Seirin..........................................Shutoku
How are we supposed to stop him?
This isn't good.
（笠松）まじぃな
いよいよ誠凛 限界だな
It looks like Seirin has reached its limit.
Amazing, amazing.
すげえ すげえ
We've got nothing to do.
（木村）つうかオレらは退屈
Kimura, lend me that pineapple.
（宮地）木村
やっぱパイナップル貸して
He's strong.
（火神）強(つえ)ぇ…
This is Midorima.
これが緑間
Kagami always laughs when he's up against a strong opponent,
（日向）火神は強敵を
目のあたりにしたとき 笑う…
けど… 何か変だ
but something's not right.
ハア
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
I won't lose! I won't!
（火神）負けるか 絶対
There's still life in your eyes, Kagami.
（緑間）目は死んでいないな 火神
だが オレのシュートは落ちん
But I'm not going to miss.
I'll stop you!
（火神）止めてみせる
もっと もっとだ
More! More!
（緑間）
これでとどめなのだよ 誠凛
This ends now, Seirin!
I don't want to lose!
（火神）負けるのなんて真っ平だ！
Episode 12
What Is "Victory"?